

# CONTACT



Stanford-Le-Hope, Essex



saimakhanom@gmail.com



07535406716



www.saimakhanom.com



www.linkedin.com/in/saimakhanom



https://github.com/saimakhanom/saimas-website

### SKILLS SUMMARY

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript ES6
- REACT.JS
- Bootstrap
- ESLint
- SQL (in progress)
- Git/GitHub

# **EDUCATION**

Sep 2018-Feb 2020 | Greenwich University
Postgraduate Certificate of Education
(PGCE) in Secondary Science with Biology

# Sep 2015-Jun 2018 | King's College London

Graduated with upper second-class honours (2.1) in Neuroscience BSc

# Sep 2013-Jun 2015 | London Academy of Excellence

A Levels: Biology (A\*) Religious Studies (A) Chemistry (B)

# Sep 2008-Jun 2013 | Azhar Academy Girls School

GCSEs: 9 A\*-B GCSEs: English (A\*A\*) Mathematics (B) and Science (AA)

# Saima Khanom

Portfolio: <a href="https://www.saimakhanom.com">www.saimakhanom.com</a> (Built from scratch using React)
References available on request

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Saima is a former teacher with over 7 years of teaching experience in various education settings. She has recently left the education sector to pursue a career in software development. She is skilled in frontend languages such as HTML, CSS, JS and React.JS as demonstrated by her portfolio website which was built from scratch using React. She is currently learning backend languages such as SQL to expand her skill set. Saima aims to become a React Developer as a stepping stone to becoming a full-stack engineer. Her problem-solving approach to coding and ability to master new skills quickly lends itself to the creation and maintenance of functional and quality websites.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Designing and developing re-usable React components (function and class-based) to allow re-use of code and to speed up development time
- Good knowledge of programming concepts such as objects, arrays, scoping, functions and variables
- Debugging code with devtools and ESLint, to ensure high code quality
- Knowledge of states, hooks and APIs, including use of Axios to obtain and update data from APIs
- Following documentation to ensure code is up to date
- Using CSS tools such as media queries, Grid and Flexbox as well as React Bootstrap components to produce visually pleasing user-interfaces and responsive web design
- Using git to track changes with add, commit, push and pull, as well as branching and merging strategies
- Using NPM to take advantage of external libraries and packages
- Using Heroku to deploy React applications into production through a build pipeline
- Using SQL to build and update databases and retrieve data
- Pair programming with other coders and working collaboratively to complete projects
- Completing various courses to expand skill set such as coding with companies such as SHECODES and CODECADEMY, as well as the Harris Diploma in Team Leadership (HDTL), and REED courses in project management and leadership

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Oct 2015 Private GCSE and A-Level Science Tutor

Present

- Communicating with students and parents to capture needs to understand the type of service that will be suitable for their educational needs
- Being empathetic with students to show that I understand their learning challenges and offering various educational solutions to meet the needs of the client
- Reaching out to other teachers when tutoring students with special needs in order to understand how to meet their needs better demonstrating I am not afraid to reach out to those who know better when I am unsure

### Mar 2020 -Feb 2022

#### **Teacher of Science & Most Able Co-ordinator**

Harris Academy Chafford Hundred / Riverside

- Using analysis of performance data to drive the development of new and engaging strategies to support struggling students, evidencing the ability to think creatively
- Leading programmes on developing students using engaging and innovative strategies such as entering students into nationwide competitions evidencing an ability to lead and think creatively
- Leading the Outreach Programme for Cyber First Girls Competition to provide girls who are interested in tech an opportunity to ascertain what a career in tech could entail and increase gender diversity in a male dominated industry
- Acting as the Technology & Document Management Lead for the department in transitioning to the use of Microsoft Teams and creating new processes for all departmental work to be saved onto MS Teams during the lockdown demonstrating natural problem-solving ability and creative thinking
- Fulfilling multiple whole school leadership roles alongside a full teaching timetable and pastoral responsibilities to an exceptional standard, demonstrating commitment to the job as well as effective organisational and time management skills

# Jun 2018 -Present

#### **Multiple Social Media Businesses Owner (Wedding Business)**

- Listening to the needs of customers, asking relevant questions, uncovering any barriers to service
  delivery and capturing the needs of customers accurately, enhancing attention to detail and ability
  to provide first class customer service
- Communicating with customers in a straightforward manner and adopting an approachable style, developing communication skills appropriate for all business environments
- Adapting customer engagement techniques depending on the type of customer and the service package they are looking to purchase (e.g., corporate or individual) displaying deep understanding of customer engagement techniques and how to tailor them to meet the needs of the customer
- Using data and insights from successful business leads to inform marketing strategy for attracting potential new clients

### Sep 2018 -Feb 2020

#### **Trainee Teacher**

#### Robert Clack School/Barking Abbey School (PGCE Placements)

- Putting students and their requirements at the heart of my teaching, developing deep understanding for the service I am providing and how that should be tailored towards the students taught
- Responsible for delivering high quality of teaching and improving student grades whilst contributing towards departmental objectives enhancing ability to achieve personal and departmental objectives simultaneously
- Using feedback to develop own teaching methodologies by implementing practices from those more experienced
- Establishing shared learning groups with other Trainee Teachers to provide a platform for challenges and learning to be shared, evidencing a desire to learn and share best practice

# Oct 2015 -Feb 2019

### **Evening and Weekend Teacher**

**Azhar Academy School** 

- Identifying emerging issues/challenges associated with student learning, using innovating techniques to address them and sharing this insight with team and the rest of the school
- Maintaining high expectations of students by expecting them to undertake independent preparation of content to be studied before taught lessons
- Building strong relationships with each student inside and outside the classroom by focusing on their interests such that students feel comfortable to approach me when in need of support and guidance, and helping to increase their confidence and love for the subject

#### INTERESTS

- Attend gym regularly to keep fit
- Constantly learning new and creative skills including crocheting, embroidery, oil painting. Currently learning digital art and sewing
- Starting and running multiple successful social media businesses based on the new skills learnt